John Hudson Cartoons
John Hudson Cartoons
1957-1969
1962-1969
Hudson, John.
7.1 linear ft.
Over 1000 original editorial cartoons and one newspaper article about Hudson's retirement.
2649261
Biographical History
John Hudson (1902-1989) was an American editorial cartoonist.
Born in Portsmouth, Ohio in 1902, John I. Hudson grew up with artistic parents and his father was a civil engineer who was interested in politics. Hudson knew he wanted to pursue cartooning while in high school and attended the Chicago Academy of Fine Arts.
One of Hudson’s first jobs was with the Columbus Citizen and he went on to work for several other Ohio newspapers including the Cleveland News and the Toledo Blade. But in 1960, Hudson moved to Phoenix, Arizona and became the editorial cartoonist for the Phoenix Gazette. Hudson remained there until his retirement in 1969 and was replaced by Bert Whitman. While at the Phoenix Gazette his cartoons were syndicated nationally.
His work was recognized with several awards including a 1942 Distinguished Service Award from the U.S. Treasury Department and six awards from the Cleveland Newspaper Guild (1949, 1951, 1953, 1955-1957). In 1960, he won the "Best Editorial Cartoon Award” from the Arizona Press Club of which he was a member and he was also presented with three George Washington awards from the Freedoms Foundation. Hudson held membership in the National Cartoonists Society and the Association of American Editorial Cartoonists.
John Hudson died in Escondido, California on April 7, 1989.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The John Hudson Cartoons are divided into two series. Cartoons consists of over 1,000 original editorial cartoons. One cartoon is from Hudson's tenure at the Cleveland News while the rest are from the Phoenix Gazette (1960-1969). The Cleveland News cartoon depicts the Supreme Court decision of 1957 which broke up Dupont's shareholder powers in General Motors. Also included are Hudson's first (August 16, 1960) and final (June 26, 1969) cartoons for the Phoenix Gazette.
While at the Phoenix Gazette, Hudson's cartoons illustrated a multitude of issues of global, national and local importance. Several cartoons address Arizona's struggles with water and in drawing Arizona Senator Barry Goldwater, particularly during his 1964 presidential campaign, Hudson commented on the shift of political power from the East (common depicted as corrupt New York politicians) to the increasingly important Sunbelt region. Also of interest are Hudson's cartoons portraying strong opposition to college students involved in the anti-war movement and draft resisters. Finally, a recurring theme was Hudson's Valentine's Day cartoon, which reminded readers of the upcoming April 15 tax deadline with Uncle Sam as their Valentine.
Each cartoon has a production sticker on the back. Specific dates are provided for many cartoons, while others are marked in pencil with years only. However 158 cartoons lack any date information. The cartoons were drawn on illustration board with ink and crayon. Traces of pencil and blue pencil are visible.
The Clippings series contains a single photocopy of a newspaper article about Hudson's retirement which appeared in the Phoenix Gazette on June 26, 1969.
Arrangement of the Collection
The cartoons are arranged in chronological order with completely undated cartoons appearing at the end of the collection.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Hudson, John.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Goldwater, Barry M. (Barry Morris), 1909-1998 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1894-1971 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States. Congress -- Caricatures and cartoons.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- Arizona.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- Arizona.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Cold War -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Editorial cartoons -- Arizona.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; Elections -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Inflation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Strikes and lockouts -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Student protesters -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Taxation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cuba -- Foreign relations -- United States -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Soviet Union -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government, 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World politics -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Editorial cartoons.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of John Hudson, 1967-1969.
Inventory
- Cartoons, 1093 items 11" x 15"; Click here for a detailed inventory of dates. See below for an index to the cartoons.
  - Cartoons, 1957; for the Cleveland News; 1 item (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, 1960; 7 items (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons, 1961; 18 items (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, 1961; 15 items (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons, 1962; 15 items (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons, 1962; 15 items (Oversize 1, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons, 1962; 19 items (Oversize 1, Folder 7)
  - Cartoons, 1963 Jan - May; 16 items (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, 1963 Jun - Oct; 17 items (Oversize 2, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons, 1963 Nov - Dec; 4 items (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, 1963; 15 items (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons, 1963; 15 items (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons, 1963; 18 items (Oversize 2, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons, 1964 Jan - Jun; 22 items (Oversize 2, Folder 7)
  - Cartoons, 1964 Jul - Dec; 21 items (Oversize 2, Folder 8)
  - Cartoons, 1964; 12 items (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, 1964; 9 items (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons, 1964; 13 items (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, 1964; 10 items (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons, 1964; 11 items (Oversize 3, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons, 1964; 13 items (Oversize 3, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons, 1964; 13 items (Oversize 3, Folder 7)
  - Cartoons, 1964; 13 items (Oversize 3, Folder 8)
  - Cartoons, 1965 Jan - Feb; 12 items (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, 1965 Apr - May; 12 items (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons, 1965 Jun- Sept; 15 items (Oversize 4, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, 1965 Oct - Nov; 18 items (Oversize 4, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons, 1965 Dec; 13 items (Oversize 4, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons, 1965; 15 items (Oversize 4, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons, 1965; 13 items (Oversize 4, Folder 7)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Jan; 14 items (Oversize 5, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Feb; 11 items (Oversize 5, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Mar; 9 items (Oversize 5, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Apr - May; 17 items (Oversize 5, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Jun; 15 items (Oversize 5, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Jul; 17 items (Oversize 5, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Aug; 25 items (Oversize 5, Folder 7)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Sep; 9 items (Oversize 6, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Oct; 15 items (Oversize 6, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons, 1966 Nov - Dec; 16 items (Oversize 6, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, 1966; 19 items (Oversize 6, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons, 1967 Jan; 12 items (Oversize 6, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons, 1967 Feb; 14 items (Oversize 6, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons, 1967 Mar; 11 items (Oversize 6, Folder 7)
  - Cartoons, 1967 Apr- Jun; 1967 Aug; 14 items (Oversize 6, Folder 8)
  - Cartoons, 1967 Sep; 14 items (Oversize 7, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, 1967 Oct; 13 items (Oversize 7, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons, 1967 Nov; 13 items (Oversize 7, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, 1967 Dec; 11 items (Oversize 7, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons, 1968 Jan; 18 items (Oversize 7, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons, 1968 Feb; 15 items (Oversize 7, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons, 1968 Mar; 12 items (Oversize 7, Folder 7)
  - Cartoons, 1968 Apr; 16 items (Oversize 7, Folder 8)
  - Cartoons, 1968 May; 6 items (Oversize 7, Folder 9)
  - Cartoons, 1968 Jun; 12 items (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, 1968 Jul; 15 items (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons, 1968 Aug; 15 items (Oversize 8, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, 1968 Sep; 14 items (Oversize 8, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons, 1968 Oct; 17 items (Oversize 8, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons, 1968 Nov; 9 items (Oversize 8, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons, 1968 Dec; 15 items (Oversize 8, Folder 7)
  - Cartoons, 1969 Jan; 10 items (Oversize 9, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, 1969 Feb; 12 items (Oversize 9, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons, 1969 Mar; 12 items (Oversize 9, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, 1969 Apr; 16 items (Oversize 9, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons, 1969 May; 12 items (Oversize 9, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons, 1969 Jun; 16 items (Oversize 9, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons, undated; 18 items (Oversize 9, Folder 7)
  - Cartoons, undated; 15 items (Oversize 9, Folder 8)
  - Cartoons, undated; 15 items (Oversize 10, Folder 1)
  - Cartoons, undated; 15 items (Oversize 10, Folder 2)
  - Cartoons, undated; 15 items (Oversize 10, Folder 3)
  - Cartoons, undated; 15 items (Oversize 10, Folder 4)
  - Cartoons, undated; 15 items (Oversize 10, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons, undated; 15 items (Oversize 10, Folder 6)
  - Cartoons, undated; 15 items (Oversize 10, Folder 7)
  - Cartoons, undated; 20 items (Oversize 10, Folder 8)
- Clippings
  - Article about Hudson's retirement from the Phoenix Gazette, 26 Jun 1969; photocopy of the original (Oversize 1)
Index to cartoons
The following is a list of predominant people, places and subjects appearing in the editorial cartoons in this collection. The list is not exhaustive. Some subjects may require you to browse with alternative terms.
B= Box, F= Folder. For example: B1F1= Box 1 Folder 1.
26th Amendment B8F1
Adenauer, Konrad B1F7
Africa B1F6 B2F6 B5F1-B5F2 B6F5 B6F7 B8F7 B9F8 B10F4
airline industry B1F7 B5F6-B5F7 B6F4 B7F8 B8F7 B10F7
Alabama B2F1
Alaska B4F6
Algeria B1F5-B1F6 B2F4-B2F6
Ali, Muhammad B5F5
aluminum industry B4F4 B10F6
anti-missile systems B8F2 B9F4
Appalachia B4F6
Arizona B1F3 B1F7 B2F5 B3F5 B4F5 B5F1 B6F4 B6F7 B7F2-B7F3 B8F1 B8F4 B9F4-B9F5
armed forces B3F5 B3F8 B4F2-B4F3 B4F6-B4F7 B5F6 B10F4 B10F7
arts B6F4
Asia B1F6 B2F3 B2F6 B5F1
Australia B5F2 B6F2 B10F2
auto industry B7F1
automobile accidents B1F2
Baker, Bobby B3F1
Bay of Pigs B1F4
Bella, Ahmed Ben B2F4 B2F6
Berlin B1F3-B1F7 B2F2-B2F4 B2F6 B4F3 B8F1 B9F2 B9F8 B10F7-B10F8
bossism B6F7
Boy Scouts B9F2
Brazil B9F2 B10F8
Brezhnev, Leonid Ilyich B2F8 B4F1 B4F3-B4F4 B4F6-B4F7 B6F3-B6F4 B6F7 B7F1 B7F5 B8F2 B10F7-B10F8
Britain B1F6 B2F1 B2F7 B3F4 B3F7 B5F4 B5F6-B5F7 B6F4 B7F1 B7F3 B7F5 B9F2 B9F5 B9F7 B10F1 B10F5
budget B2F1 B2F5 B3F1-B3F2 B3F5 B3F8 B4F5 B5F1 B6F3 B6F5 B7F6 B10F2
Burger, Warren B9F6
business B1F1 B1F5 B2F6 B10F2
Byrd, Harry B1F2 B2F6
California B3F1 B6F3-B6F4 B7F1 B9F2
Cambodia B2F7 B4F6 B5F7 B9F4
Canada B3F4 B4F4 B5F5 B10F2 B10F5
capitalism B2F7
Castro, Fidel B1F3-B1F4 B1F6 B2F1 B2F3-B2F5 B3F1 B4F6 B5F1 B5F5 B5F7 B6F3 B6F5 B7F1 B7F5 B7F7 B8F5 B9F3 B9F7-B10F1 B10F4-B10F6
children B1F3 B2F2 B4F3
China B1F3-B1F4 B1F6-B1F7 B3F1 B3F7-B3F8 B4F2-B4F4 B4F6-B4F7 B5F3-B5F4 B5F6 B6F1-B6F2 B6F4-B6F5 B6F7 B7F1-B7F3 B7F6 B8F6 B9F2 B9F8 B10F7
Churchill, Winston B2F1 B4F1
cities B2F4 B10F4
civil rights B1F6 B2F1-B2F2 B2F4 B2F6-B3F2 B5F6 B6F7 B7F4 B7F7 B9F7
Cold War B2F4 B8F1
college professors B6F4
college students B4F2 B5F2 B6F4 B7F9-B8F1 B8F4-B8F5 B9F3-B9F7
Colorado B6F4
Columbia University B7F9 B8F4
Columbus, Christopher B4F7
common market B2F2 B9F2 B9F5 B10F8
communism B1F2-B1F3 B1F7 B2F4-B2F5 B2F7-B2F8 B3F2 B3F6 B4F1 B4F3-B4F5 B5F2 B5F5-B6F1 B6F3 B6F7 B7F4 B8F4 B9F3 B9F5 B9F7 B10F1 B10F4 B10F6
Congo B1F2-B1F4 B1F6 B2F1 B2F3-B2F6 B3F7 B5F6 B9F7-B9F8 B10F3 B10F6-B10F8
Congress B1F3 B1F5-B3F3 B3F5 B3F7 B4F1 B4F3-B4F4 B4F6-B5F7 B6F2 B6F4-B6F7 B7F2 B7F4-B8F4 B9F1-B9F2 B9F4-B10F3 B10F5-B10F8
consumers B2F7 B4F4 B5F4 B8F4
copper mining B6F1 B7F1 B7F3 B7F5 B7F7 B10F6
cost of living B5F1 B5F4 B5F7 B6F3-B6F4 B7F8 B8F3 B9F6
crime B3F5 B4F5 B5F5 B5F7 B6F2-B6F3 B6F6-B6F7 B7F1-B7F4 B7F6 B8F3 B8F7-B9F1 B10F2-B10F4
Cuba B1F4-B2F2 B2F4-B3F1 B4F3 B4F5-B5F1 B5F6-B5F7 B6F3 B6F5 B6F7 B7F1 B7F5 B8F2 B8F5 B8F7 B9F3 B9F7-B9F8 B10F2 B10F4-B10F8
currency B2F1 B3F3 B4F6 B10F1
Cyprus B3F1 B9F7 B10F4
Czechoslovakia B1F6 B7F5 B8F2-B8F5
Daley, Richard J. B8F3
de Gaulle, Charles B3F2 B3F7 B5F4-B5F5 B5F7 B6F7 B7F2-B7F3 B7F5 B7F7 B7F9-B8F1 B8F4 B9F2 B9F4 B9F6 B10F4-B10F6
debt B3F5 B4F2-B4F3 B6F6 B9F1
defense B1F3 B1F5 B2F2 B3F3 B9F7
Democratic Party B2F8 B3F2 B3F8 B5F6 B6F1 B6F3 B6F7 B7F7-B7F8 B8F2-B8F4 B8F6 B10F3 B10F6
demonstrations B4F3-B4F4 B5F3 B6F7 B7F2 B7F4 B8F1 B8F3-B8F4 B9F3-B9F6
Dewey, Thomas B2F8 B3F6
Dirksen, Everett B4F3 B5F1
disarmament B2F1 B4F3 B5F7 B10F2 B10F6
discrimination B4F7
Dominican Republic B3F1 B3F6 B4F2-B4F3 B4F5 B4F7 B6F4 B10F3 B10F5-B10F6
draft B4F4 B5F3 B5F5 B6F6-B6F7 B7F2 B7F4
economy B2F2 B2F4 B2F6 B5F5 B5F7 B6F6-B6F7 B7F2 B10F2
education B2F1 B2F4 B4F4 B4F7 B5F7-B6F2 B6F4 B7F2 B9F1 B9F5 B10F4
Egypt B2F4 B4F4
Eisenhower, Dwight B1F4 B1F7-B2F1 B2F7 B3F4 B9F7
elections B1F4-B1F5 B1F7 B2F2 B2F4-B3F8 B4F3 B5F3 B6F1-B6F4 B6F7 B7F1 B7F3-B7F4 B7F6-B8F6 B9F2-B9F3 B9F7 B10F6-B10F8
electoral college B4F1
Erhard, Ludwig B6F3
espionage B1F3 B2F3
Ethiopia B1F2
Europe B1F5-B1F6 B2F2 B2F4 B5F4 B6F7 B9F2 B10F5 B10F8
fallout shelters B2F2
Fannin, Paul B1F7
farming B1F3 B1F6-B2F1 B4F7 B5F4 B9F3-B9F4 B10F5
Federal Bureau of Investigation B1F3 B7F8 B9F1
Florida B4F5 B10F4
food prices B2F7
foreign aid B1F3 B1F5-B1F6 B2F1-B2F6 B3F1 B3F5 B4F2-B4F3 B5F5 B6F3-B6F4 B6F6-B6F7 B7F4 B8F2 B8F4 B9F5-B9F6 B10F1 B10F5-B10F6
foreign policy B1F4 B2F4 B2F8 B3F2 B4F2 B4F6
forest fires B5F5 B10F7
founding fathers B1F3-B1F4
France B1F5-B1F6 B2F6 B3F7 B5F1 B5F4 B6F7 B7F7 B8F1 B9F4 B9F6 B10F4
freedom B4F2 B5F6 B6F3 B8F1-B8F2
freedom of information B5F6
Fulbright, J. William B5F4 B7F6 B9F7
Gaza B9F7
George III B5F4
Germany B1F5 B6F3 B8F4 B9F2-B9F3
gold B5F2
gold reserve B1F7 B3F2 B7F3 B7F5 B7F7 B10F4
Goldwater, Barry B1F2 B1F6-B1F7 B2F6-B3F8 B6F3 B8F3 B9F7 B10F1 B10F5-B10F8
government spending B1F4-B1F5 B2F1-B2F2 B3F7 B4F4 B5F7 B6F2 B7F2 B10F4-B10F5 B10F7
graduates B5F5
Great Society B3F5 B4F2 B4F5-B4F6 B5F1-B5F2 B6F2-B6F5 B10F1-B10F2 B10F6
Greenland B7F5
Gromyko, Andrei B2F4 B10F7
Guam B6F7
Guantanamo Bay B2F2 B2F4 B10F5
gun control B8F1-B8F2
Haiti B3F1 B4F2 B6F3
Halleck, Charles B4F2
Hammarskjold, Dag B10F8
healthcare B5F7 B7F4
highway construction B6F3
hijacking B1F7 B2F4 B8F2 B8F7
Ho Chi Minh B5F2-B5F3 B5F6 B6F3-B6F4 B6F7 B7F1 B7F3 B9F3-B9F4 B9F6
Hoffa, Jimmy B6F7 B10F7
holidays B1F2-B1F3 B1F5 B3F6 B4F4-B4F5 B5F6 B6F3 B7F3-B7F4 B8F2-B8F3 B10F1 B10F6
Hong Kong B7F1
Hoover, J. Edgar B9F1
housing B3F2
Humphrey, Hubert B3F6 B3F8 B5F2 B6F7 B7F6 B7F8 B8F3 B9F7
Hungary B1F7 B8F2 B10F6
Hussein of Jordan B9F4
immigration B10F1
India B1F3 B4F3 B4F7 B5F2 B9F8 B10F7
Indonesia B4F6-B4F7 B5F6 B6F4 B7F2 B9F8-B10F1
inflation B1F4 B4F5 B5F3-B5F5 B5F7-B6F4 B7F2-B7F3 B7F5 B8F4 B8F7 B9F2 B9F4
insurance B3F5
Internal Revenue Service B6F4
Iran B1F2 B10F6
Ireland B6F7
Israel B5F5 B6F3 B6F7 B9F1 B9F3
Japan B5F2
Javits, Jacob B3F2 B8F3
Johnson, Luci B. B4F4
Johnson, Lyndon Baines B2F3 B2F5 B2F8 B3F1-B3F2 B3F5-B3F6 B3F8 B4F2-B4F5 B4F7-B5F2 B5F7-B6F2 B6F4-B6F7 B7F2 B7F5-B7F6 B7F8 B9F7-B9F8 B10F4-B10F8
Jordan B6F3
judicial system B7F7
justice B6F2
juvenile delinquency B10F1 B10F5
Kadar, Janos B10F5-B10F6
Keating, Kenneth B2F8
Kennedy, John F. B1F2-B2F1 B2F4 B2F6 B2F8 B9F7-B10F2 B10F5 B10F7-B10F8
Kennedy, Robert F. B1F7 B7F8 B8F1 B9F7
Kennedy, Ted B1F7 B3F7 B8F3 B9F7
Khrushchev, Nikita B1F2-B3F3 B3F7-B3F8 B4F6 B9F7-B9F8 B10F2-B10F8
King Jr., Martin Luther B7F8
Korea B2F3 B2F6 B2F7 B10F7
Korean War B7F6
Kosygin, Alexey B4F1 B4F3 B4F6 B5F5 B8F2 B8F5 B10F8
Ky, Nguyen Cao B6F2
labor B2F5-B2F6 B3F5 B4F4 B6F1
Laos B1F6-B1F7 B2F4 B2F6 B3F1 B3F7 B10F4 B10F7-B10F8
Latin America B1F3 B1F5-B1F6 B2F4 B5F5 B10F4-B10F5 B10F8
law and order B6F7 B8F5 B9F5
liberty B5F6 B9F7 B10F3 B10F6
Lincoln, Abraham B3F4 B4F1 B6F6 B9F2
Lindsay, John B4F4 B8F3
Lodge Jr., Henry Cabot B2F7-B2F8 B3F4 B3F6 B3F8 B10F1
MacArthur, Douglas B1F3
MacMillan, Harold B3F4
Maddox, Lester B8F3
Malaysia B4F7 B5F2
Mansfield, Mike B2F1
Massachusetts B1F7
McCarthy, Eugene B7F6 B7F8 B8F3
McCormack, Eddie B3F7
McGovern, George B8F3
McNamara, Robert B2F8 B5F4 B6F4 B6F7 B7F1 B10F8
meat industry B1F6
Medicare B1F4 B1F6 B2F1 B2F6 B3F1-B3F2 B4F3 B4F7 B5F5-B5F6 B6F4 B10F2 B10F5
Mexico B5F6 B8F4
Middle East B2F3 B6F3 B6F7 B7F1 B7F5 B9F1-B9F3 B9F7 B10F3 B10F7
Mississippi B9F7
Mongolia B1F4
Monroe Doctrine B2F6 B4F2 B10F5
Morocco B2F6
Morse, Wayne B4F2 B5F4
Moscow Pact B2F3 B10F1 B10F5
Nasser, Gamal Abdel B2F4 B5F5 B10F7
national debt B3F3 B9F4 B9F7 B10F5
National Farm Organization B1F6
NATO B1F6 B2F4 B3F7 B5F4 B9F2 B9F4 B9F8
natural disasters B1F3 B4F6 B5F1 B10F6
natural resources B3F5 B6F4 B8F1 B8F4
Nehru, Jawaharlal B1F3 B9F8
Nevada B6F4
New Frontier B2F1 B2F3 B2F5-B2F6 B10F6
New Mexico B6F4 B10F5
New York B2F6 B3F1
New York City B4F4 B4F6 B7F6 B8F5 B10F1 B10F4
Nigeria B8F7
Nixon, Richard M. B1F2 B1F7 B2F7 B3F1 B3F6-B3F8 B7F2 B7F5-B7F6 B7F8 B8F3 B8F6-B9F6
Nkrumah, Kwame B5F2
North Korea B1F4 B1F7 B7F6 B9F2 B9F4
nuclear weapons B1F4 B2F2-B2F7 B3F7-B3F8 B4F6 B5F3-B5F4 B7F5 B8F4 B10F3 B10F5 B10F7-B10F8
Ohio B2F5
oil B5F4 B7F5
Olympics B8F4
Organization of American States B1F4 B4F2 B9F7-B9F8 B10F3
organized crime B5F6 B9F3-B9F4
Pakistan B4F3 B4F7
Panama B3F1 B4F4 B4F6 B7F7 B8F5 B10F6
Panama Canal B5F1 B6F1 B9F6-B9F7 B10F1-B10F2 B10F5
peace B2F6 B3F6 B4F3 B4F5 B5F1 B5F7 B6F2-B6F3 B6F7 B7F2 B7F6 B7F8-B8F1 B8F6-B8F7 B9F3 B9F5-B9F6
Peace Corps B1F3
Pentagon B1F3 B2F5 B3F3 B5F7
Percy, Charles H. B7F6
Peru B9F2 B9F5
Philippines B4F4 B6F2
piracy B9F2
police B6F5
politicians B3F2 B5F7 B8F5
politics B2F1 B2F5-B2F6 B2F8-B3F1 B5F7 B6F2 B6F7 B8F5
pollution B4F4 B9F1
Pope John XXIII B3F4
poverty B2F6 B3F1 B10F2-B10F3
Powell, Adam Clayton B9F6
prayer B1F7
press B1F5 B1F7 B2F2 B3F4 B6F2 B7F7 B10F3
prices B1F6
Puerto Rico B9F3
railroad industry B2F2 B2F5-B2F6 B3F6 B5F5-B5F7 B6F4 B10F8
Reagan, Ronald B6F3 B7F2 B7F6 B8F3
Republican Party B1F7 B2F7-B2F8 B3F2-B3F4 B3F7-B3F8 B5F1 B5F6-B6F1 B6F3 B6F5 B7F2 B7F7 B8F3-B8F4 B8F6-B8F7 B9F4 B10F5-B10F6
restaurant industry B2F1
Rhodesia B5F4 B6F5 B8F4 B8F6
right to work law B3F5
riots B5F6-B5F7 B6F4 B6F7 B7F1-B7F2 B7F4-B7F6 B9F5
Rockefeller, Nelson B2F2 B3F7 B3F3-B3F4 B3F6-B3F8 B7F2 B7F6 B7F8-B7F9 B8F2-B8F3 B9F6 B10F1 B10F5-B10F6 B10F8
Romania B8F4
Romney, George W. B3F6 B6F3 B7F2 B7F6-B7F7
Roosevelt, Eleanor B9F8
Rusk, Dean B2F8 B5F4
Russia B1F3 B1F5-B1F6 B2F8 B4F2-B4F6 B5F5 B6F1 B6F4 B6F6 B7F1 B8F7 B9F7 B10F2 B10F5 B10F7
Saudi Arabia B6F3
school dropouts B2F2 B7F1
schools B1F5 B7F1
science B2F5 B10F2
Scranton, William B2F7-B3F1 B3F4 B3F6 B3F8
SEATO B1F6
Selassie, Haile B1F2
Singapore B4F7
Sinyavsky Daniel trial B5F2
slums B2F6
Smith, Margaret Chase B2F7 B3F8 B10F1
smoking B7F7 B9F4
social security B3F1 B6F2 B10F1-B10F2
socialism B1F3
South America B6F7 B7F2 B9F2 B9F6
Soviet Union B1F4 B1F7 B2F2-B2F3 B2F5-B2F6 B2F7-B2F8 B3F6 B3F8 B4F6-B5F1 B5F4 B6F1 B6F6-B6F7 B7F2 B7F5-B7F6 B8F1-B8F5 B9F2 B9F4 B10F1 B10F8
space exploration B1F4 B1F7 B2F2 B2F5-B2F6 B4F3 B4F5 B4F7 B5F4-B5F5 B5F7-B6F1 B6F5 B7F2 B8F5 B8F7 B9F5-B9F7 B10F2-B10F3
Speck, Richard B6F6
sports B4F7 B6F2 B7F1-B7F2 B8F5 B10F4
Stalin, Joseph B1F3
Stassen, Harold B2F7 B3F3 B3F8 B7F3 B7F6
states' rights B1F7
steel industry B2F5-B2F6 B2F8 B4F4 B4F7-B5F1 B5F7 B8F3 B9F8 B10F6
Stevenson, Adlai E. B2F8
stock market B10F2
strikes B1F6 B2F1-B2F2 B2F5 B5F7 B6F3-B6F4 B6F7 B7F1-B7F2 B7F6-B7F8 B8F2-B8F3 B8F5 B9F4 B9F8 B10F7
Students for a Democratic Society B9F5
Sukarno B4F4 B5F3-B5F4 B5F6 B6F4
Supreme Court B1F1 B1F7 B2F6 B2F7-B3F2 B4F3 B5F5 B6F6 B7F1 B8F2 B8F4 B9F5 B10F2-B10F3
Sweden B7F5
Syria B6F3
Tahiti B5F7
taxes B1F3-B1F6 B2F1-B2F2 B2F4-B2F7 B3F4-B3F6 B3F8-B4F5 B4F7-B5F1 B5F3-B5F7 B6F2-B6F6 B7F2-B7F9 B8F2-B8F3 B8F5 B8F7-B9F7 B10F1-B10F5 B10F7-B10F8
teachers B7F1 B7F6-B7F7 B8F5
telecommunication B3F7 B7F8 B10F7
television B1F7 B7F4 B10F4
Thant, U. B3F3 B4F1 B5F5 B6F1 B6F7 B8F4-B8F5 B9F7 B10F4 B10F6 B10F8
Thieu, Nguyen Van B9F6
Tito, Josip Broz B2F2 B8F5
tourism B7F6-B7F7
trade B1F5 B2F2 B2F7 B7F7 B10F4 B10F7
transportation B1F6 B2F5-B2F6 B3F1 B5F7 B6F4
Truman, Harry S. B5F7
U.S. Constitution B1F7 B2F7
U.S. Flag B2F2
U.S. Postal Service B7F5 B8F2 B9F5
Udall, Mo B1F7 B7F2
Udall, Stewart B1F7
unemployment B2F4 B10F1
unions B6F3 B7F7
United Nations B1F3-B1F4 B1F6-B2F4 B2F6 B2F8 B3F4 B3F6-B3F7 B4F1-B4F2 B5F1 B5F5 B6F1 B6F5 B6F7 B7F3 B8F4-B8F6 B9F6-B10F1 B10F3 B10F5-B10F8
University of California-Berkeley B5F2 B9F6
urban renewal B6F7
USS Pueblo B7F5-B7F6 B8F7 B9F4
Utah B6F4
utilities B1F5
Venezuela B2F3 B2F5
Vietnam B1F7 B2F4 B2F6
Vietnam War B2F7-B3F1 B4F1-B5F4 B5F6-B5F7 B6F2-B6F7 B7F1-B7F5 B7F7-B8F6 B9F3-B9F6 B9F8 B10F4 B10F7-B10F8
Virginia B1F2
voting B1F7 B3F5 B3F7 B10F8
Walker, Edwin A. B3F3
Wallace, George B8F4
War on Poverty B3F1 B3F4 B3F6 B4F1-B4F2 B4F6 B6F3-B6F4 B6F7 B9F2 B10F1
Warren Commission B2F8
Warren, Earl B8F2 B9F6
Washington, George B1F6 B2F4 B4F7 B5F2 B6F6 B9F2
weather B2F7 B5F1 B5F4 B9F2
welfare B1F5 B2F4 B3F1 B10F1
Westmoreland, William C. B7F7
Wilson, Harold B5F6-B5F7
women B1F7
Wyoming B6F4
Yugoslavia B1F4-B1F5 B8F5
Zanzibar B4F6
Zedong, Mao B1F4 B2F8 B4F1 B4F3-B4F4 B4F6 B5F3-B5F4 B5F7 B6F2-B6F7 B7F2-B7F3 B10F7